很久以前，在遥远的银河系…
星球大战
前传：魅影危机
银河共和国里动荡不安
为星际贸易通道上的税收问题纠纷
贪婪的贸易联盟派出战斗舰队
企图封锁一切运往纳布星系的货物
正当共和国会就这一连串危机争论不休的时候
共和国首相已经秘密派出两名
维护和平和正义的绝地武士
去解决冲突
- 船长 - 是，长官？
- Captain. - Yes, sir?
通知他们我们要登舰了
Tell them we wish to board at once.
满怀尊敬之意…
With all due respect...
共和国首相的两位特使请求立即登舰
the ambassadors for the supreme chancellor wish to board immediately.
当然可以
Yes, of course.
如你所知，我们的封锁行动是合法的…
As you know, our blockade is perfectly legal...
我们欢迎共和国特使
and we'd be happy to receive the ambassadors.
我是TC-14，欢迎两位，
I'm TC-14 at your service.
请这边走
This way, please.
特使的到访让我们倍感荣幸
We are greatly honoured by your visit, Ambassadors.
请稍候片刻
Make yourselves comfortable.
我的主人马上就到
My master will be with you shortly.
我有一种不详的感觉
I have a bad feeling about this.
- 我倒没感觉到  - 我不是说这次任务，师父
- I don't sense anything. - It's not about the mission, Master.
是一种模糊的预感
It's something elsewhere, elusive.
你过于焦虑不安了，欧比旺
Don't centre on your anxieties, Obi-Wan.
你应该把注意力放在这里，注意这里的情况
Keep your concentration here and now, where it belongs.
可是尤达师父告诉我应该留意未来
But Master Yoda said I should be mindful of the future.
那也不能不顾眼前的情况
But not at the expense of the moment.
要欣赏生命的原动力，年轻的绝地学徒
Be mindful of the living Force, young Padawan.
是，师父
Yes, Master.
贸易总督会怎样回应首相的要求呢？
How do you think this trade viceroy will deal with the chancellor's demands?
贸易联盟的人都是懦夫
These Federation types are cowards.
谈判会很快结束的
The negotiations will be short.
什么？你说什么？
What? What did you say?
我看这两位特使一定是绝地武士
The ambassadors are Jedi knights, I believe.
我知道
I knew it.
他们来迫使我们答应条件
They're here to force a settlement.
稳住他们，我来联系西迪厄斯大人
Distract them. I will contact Lord Sidious.
你疯了吗？
Are you brain-dead?
我才不去见那两个绝地武士
I'm not going in there with two Jedi.
派机器人去吧
Send a droid.
让我们等这么久是他们的习惯吗？
Is it in their nature to make us wait this long?
不 我察觉到一种不同寻常的恐惧…
No. I sense an unusual amount of fear...
对解决贸易纠纷的谈判不太相干
for something as trivial as this trade dispute.
什么事啊？
What is it?
你的计划失败了，西迪厄斯大人
This scheme of yours has failed, Lord Sidious.
封锁结束了，我们不敢对抗绝地武士
The blockade is finished. We dare not go against these Jedi.
总督，别叫这胆小鬼再出现我眼前
Viceroy, I don't want this stunted slime in my sight again.
很不幸事情出现变化，要速战速决
This turn of events is unfortunate. We must accelerate our plans.
叫你的军队开始登陆
Begin landing your troops.
大人，那样做合法吗？
My lord, is that legal?
我会让它合法的
I will make it legal.
绝地武士怎么办？
And the Jedi?
首相根本不应派他们来
The chancellor should never have brought them into this.
立即干掉他们
Kill them immediately.
是，大人，一定照办
Yes, my lord . As you wish.
船长，看！
Captain, look!
启动防护罩…
Shields...
抱歉
Sorry.
是毒气
Dioxis.
他们应该已经死了
They must be dead by now.
若未死的话，干掉他们
Destroy what's left of them.
噢，对不起
Oh! Excuse me.
- 查看一下，下士，我会掩护你的 - 收到，收到
- Check it out, Corporal. We'll cover you. - Roger, roger.
干掉他们
Blast them.
下面出什么事了？
What is going on down there?
通讯中断了，长官
We lost the transmission, sir.
你曾经和绝地武士交过手吗？
Have you ever encountered a Jedi knight before, sir?
没有，封闭舰桥
Well, no, but I don't... Seal off the bridge.
- 是，长官  - 那样阻止不了他们
- Yes, sir. - That won't be enough, sir.
马上派机器人来
I want droidekas up here at once!
这下我们可要完了
We will not survive this.
关闭闸门
Close the blast doors!
这下他们进不来了
That will hold them.
我看他们仍可穿过
They are still coming through.
这怎么可能！
This is impossible!
我们的机器人怎么还不来？
Where are those droidekas?
师父！小心！
Master! Destroyers!
他们有防护罩
They have shield generators!
这是个平局，我们走
It's a standoff. Let's go.
他们挡不住机器人
They're no match for droidekas.
长官！
Sir!
他们进入了通风气道
They've gone up the ventilation shaft.
- 战斗机器人 - 这是一支入侵部队
- Battle droids. - It's an invasion army.
这是贸易联盟的诡计
This is an odd play for the Trade Federation.
我们得警告纳布星球并联系维罗伦首相
We've got to warn the Naboo and contact Chancellor Valorum.
我们分头行事
Let's split up.
藏在不同的战舰里，着陆之后再会合
Stow aboard separate ships and meet down on the planet.
有一件事你说对了，师父
You were right about one thing, Master.
谈判的确结束得很快
The negotiations were short.
长官，星球上有通讯来
Sir, a transmission from the planet.
是阿米达拉女王
It's Queen Amidala herself.
终于有结果了
At last we are getting results.
我们又见到面了，女王陛下
Again you come before us, Your Highness.
你现在别高兴得太早
You will not be so pleased when you hear what I have to say, Viceroy.
你们的贸易封锁行动已经失败了
Your trade boycott of our planet has ended.
这个我怎么不知道？
I was not aware of such failure.
我知道两位特使在你们那儿…
I have word that the chancellor's ambassadors are with you now...
要求你们马上达成协议
and that you have been commanded to reach settlement.
我没听说过什么特使
I know nothing of any ambassadors.
你一定是搞错了，陛下
You must be mistaken.
你要知道，总督
Beware, Viceroy.
联盟这次做得太过分了
The Federation has gone too far this time.
没有国会的同意我们是不敢乱来的
We would never do anything without the approval of the senate.
你是太多心了吧
You assume too much.
等着瞧吧
We will see.
- 她说的对，国会绝对不会… - 现在说这个太晚了
- She's right. The senate will never... - It's too late now.
- 她怀疑我们要进攻吗？   - 我不知道
- Do you think she suspects an attack? - I don't know.
但是必须马上切断所有同纳布星的通讯
But we must move quickly to disrupt all communications down there.
他们说共和国首相的两位特使不在那里？
Negotiations haven 't started because the ambassadors aren't there?
这怎么可能？
How could that be true?
我从首相那里得到消息是：特使们已经到了
I have assurances from the chancellor his ambassadors did arrive.
一定是…谈判…特使们…后果…
It must... handiwork... negotiate... ambassadors...
- 没有人可以… - 帕尔帕庭议员
- nobody would... - Senator Palpatine.
怎么回事？
What's happening?
检查一下通讯发射器
Check the transmission generator.
通讯中断表明贸易联盟已经…入侵了
A communications disruption can mean only one thing: invasion.
联盟现在还不敢这样
The Federation would not dare go that far.
国会有权撤消他贸易的特权，那样他们就完了
The senate would revoke their trade franchise, and they'd be finished.
我们必须继续进行谈判
We must continue to rely on negotiation.
谈判？ 通讯完全中断了
Negotiation? We've lost all communications.
又不知道特使在什么地方？
And where are the chancellor's ambassadors?
情况非常危险，女王陛下
This is a dangerous situation, Your Highness.
我们的保安志愿军兵力有限…
Our security volunteers will be no match...
抵挡不住贸易联盟的庞大军队
against a battle-hardened Federation army.
我绝不允许任何导致战争的行为
I will not condone a course of action that will lead us to war.
- 遵命，总督？ - 我们搜查了整个战舰…
- Yes, Viceroy? - Captain, we've searched the ship...
没有发现绝地武士的踪迹
and there is no trace of the Jedi.
他们也许藏在那艘登陆艇上
They may have gotten on one of your landing craft.
如果他们真的在这我们会找到的
If they're down here, sir, we'll find them.
多加小心，不要低估了这两个绝地武士
Use caution. These Jedi are not to be underestimated.
- 哦，不！ - 走开！离开这儿！
- Oh, no!  - Get away! Get out of here!
趴下！
Get down!
是什么东西？等等！Was'n dat? Hey, wait!
我爱你！
Oh, mooie-mooie, I love you.
你差点送了我们的命，你没脑筋吗？
You almost got us killed. Are you brainless?
我会说话啊
I spake.
会说话不证明你就有头脑
The ability to speak does not make you intelligent.
- 好了，快走吧  - 不，不，我得留下
- Now, get out of here. - No, no, mesa stay.
我叫加加宾可斯，你卑微的仆人
Mesa culled JarJar Binks. Mesa your humble servant.
- 我不需要仆人  - 你得需要
- That won't be necessary. - Oh, but it'tis.
这是神的旨意
'Tis demanded by the gods, it'tis.
- 哦，不！ - 快趴下！
- Oh, no!    - Stay down!
你又救了我一命
You saved my again.
- 他是谁？ - 一个当地人
- What's this? - A local.
还会有机械人来的，快走，还有？
Let's get out of here before more droids show up.
还有？你是说还有机械人要来？
More? "More" did you spake?
抱歉，但最安全的地方是冈根城
Ex-squeeze-me, but de mostest safest place would be Gunga City.
我是在那里长大的，那城市很隐蔽
Is where I grew up. 'Tis a hidden city.
- 城市？ - 是
- A city? - Uh-huh.
你来带我们去吧
Can you take us there?
那…那可不行
On second thought, no.
- 我不能带你们去 - 为什么？
- Not really, no.     - No?
说起来不好意思…
'Tis embarrassing...
我是被流放出来的
but my afraid my've been banished.
我刚才忘了，首领不会轻饶了我的
My forgotten. Da bosses would do terrible tings to me.
我要是回去了就饶不了我的
Terrible tings to me if me goen back dare.
- 你听到了吗？ - 听到了
- You hear that? - Yah.
这么大批的机器人朝着这个方向杀来
That is the sound of a thousand terrible things heading this way.
如果让他们发现了，我们可就…
If they find us, they will crush us...
粉身粹骨了，到时候我们连渣都没有了
grind us into tiny pieces and blast us into oblivion.
哦
Oh.
你说的一点不错
Yousa point is well seen.
这边走，快！
Dis way. Hurry!
- 还有多远？ - 下面的路我们得从水下走
- How much further? - Wesa goen underwater, okeyday?
我警告你们
Ah, my warning you.
冈根人不喜欢外来人，别希望他们会欢迎你们
Gungans no liken outsiders, so don't spect a warm welcome.
没关系，今天不光是他们不欢迎我们
Don't worry. This hasn't been our day for warm welcomes.
好了，你们跟我来
Yousa follow me now, okeyday?
回家的感觉真好啊！
So good bein home!
- 是加加 - 他还敢回来呀
- Oh, me gusa. - Hata-hata.
你们几个都站住
Hey, yousa. Stopa dare.
你好，塔布斯队长
Heyo-dales, Cap'n Tarpals.
我回来了
Mesa back.
你还敢回来，加加，去见首领嘛
Noah gain, JarJar. Yousa goen tada bosses.
这次你的麻烦可大了
Yousa in big dudu dis time.
真粗鲁
How wude.
你们不能留在这里
Yousa cannot bees hair.
那些机械人部队是你们招惹来的，我说的没错吧
Dis army of Mackineeks up dare is new weesong.
这些机械人部队马上就要进攻纳布城了 我们必须通知他们
A droid army is about to attack the Naboo. We must warn them.
我们不喜欢纳布城的人
Wesa no like da Naboo.
让他们自以为自己聪明
Da Naboo tink day so smarty.
总觉得自己的脑子比我们的好用
Day tink day brains so big.
机械人一旦控制了纳布城
Once those droids take control of the surface,
也就会控制了你们
they will take control of you.
.我觉得不会的
Mesa no tink so.
你根本就不知道我们
Day not know of uss-en.
你们和纳布人是共生关系
You and the Naboo form a symbiont circle.
一方所受的灾难会影响另一方
What happens to one of you will affect the other.
你必须明白
You must understand this.
纳布人是死是活跟我没有关系
Wesa no carrrre-nn about da Naboo.
那就赶快让我们走吧
Then speed us on our way.
要滚，那就快滚吧
Wesa ganna speed yous away.
可现在我们缺少交通工具
We could use a transport.
我们会给你们一艘邦高
Wesa give yousa una bongo.
到纳布城最快的途径
Da speediest way tooda Naboo...
是从行星的地心穿过去
'tis goen through the planet core.
好了…
Now...
走吧
go.
感谢你的帮助，我们会和平的离去
Thank you for your help. We leave in peace.
师父，邦高是什么东西？
Master, what's a bongo?
但愿是一座飞船
A transport, I hope.
他是在耍你们
Deysa setten yousa up.
从地心穿过去？那是会要人命的
Goen through da planet core? Bad bombin'.
学雷锋做好事嘛
Any help here would be hot.
师父，我们时间不多了
Master, we're short on time.
我们需要一位领航员才能穿过地心
We'll need a navigator to get us through the planet's core.
这个冈根人也许能帮助我们
This Gungan may be of help.
能不能告诉我们，你们要把加加怎么样？
What is to become of JarJar Binks here?
严厉惩罚
Hisen to be pune-ished.
我救过他的命
I saved his life.
所以他也欠我一条命
He owes me what you call a "life-debt."
依你们神的旨意，他的命应该是属于我的
Your gods demand that his life belongs to me now.
宾可斯…
Binks...
你真的欠他一条命吗？
yousa havena liveplay with thisen hisen?
是的
Mm, uh-huh.
那你跟他去吧！
Begone wit him!
我还是不要跟你去了吧
Count me outta dis one.
我宁可死在这也不愿死在地心里
Better dead here than dead in da core.
天哪！我在说些什么？
Yee gods! What mesa sayin?
真是疯了，是恐怖鱼！
Dis is nutsen. Oh, gooberfish!
- 你为什么被流放了，加加？ - 说来话长了…
- Why were you banished, JarJar? - It's a longo tale-o...
归根到底应该是…  我太笨了吧
buta a small part of it would be mesa... clumsy.
因为笨就把你流放吗？
You were banished for being clumsy?
也可以这么说吧
Yousa might'n be sayin dat.
我这个人太粗心，以前出过一两个小事故
Mesa caused mabee one two-y lettle bitty axadentes, huh?
爆掉一个油库…
Yud-say boom da gasser...
不小心把首领的船撞烂了，就被流放了
den crashin der boss's heyblibber, den banished.
大恐怖鱼！好大的牙齿！
Big gooberfish! Huge-o teeth!
总是大鱼吃小鱼
There's always a bigger fish.
我认为咱们还是回去吧
Mesa tink we goen back now.
入侵行动按时进行，大人
The invasion is on schedule, my lord .
我一直拖延了国会的议程
I have the senate bogged down in procedures.
他们别无选择，只有接受你对纳布城的控制
They will have no choice but to accept your control of the system.
可是艾米达拉女王坚持，国会会站在她那边
The queen has great faith that the senate will side with her.
那位阿米达拉女王年轻又幼稚
Queen Amidala is young and naive.
控制着她不会是一件困难的事
You will find controlling her will not be difficult.
是，大人
Yes, my lord .
你没跟他提那两个失踪的绝地武士
You didn't tell him about the missing Jedi.
没必要向他报告，直到我们需要报告再说
No need to report that to him until we have something to report.
- 我们这要去哪儿？ - 别担心，原力会指引我们
- Where wesa goin? - Don't worry. The Force will guide us.
嘿，好厉害的原力
Oh, maxi big, da Force.
我可不相信什么原力
Well, dat smells stinkowiff.
- 失去动力了 - 哦，不！
- We're losing power. - Oh, no!
那我们死定了
Wesa dyin' here.
- 别紧张，情况没那么严重  - 还没什么？
- Just relax. We're not in trouble yet. - What "yet"?
外面是怪物，船又漏水
Monsters out dare. Leak'n in here.
就快要沉了又没有动力？
All sink'n and no power?
都这样了还不算严重吗？
Whena yousa tinkin wesa in trouble?
动力恢复了
Power's back.
怪物回来了！
Monster's back!
别紧张
Relax.
你把它吓到了
You overdid it.
恐怖
Horrible.
去那边
Head for that outcropping.
哦，孩子
Oh, boy.
总督，我们抓到女王了
Viceroy, we have captured the queen.
哈，胜利了
Ah, victory.
这真漂亮呀
Dis'n loverly.
对此你怎么向国会作出解释？
How will you explain this invasion to the senate?
我要女王和我签署一个协议
The queen and I will sign a treaty
使我们在这里的行动合法化
that will legitimize our occupation here.
我相信国会一定会同意我这么做的
I have assurances it will be ratified by the senate.
- 我是不会合作的   - 行了，女王陛下
- I will not cooperate. - Now, now, Your Highness.
到那时，你人民蒙受苦难
In time, your people's suffering
这将会劝说你答应我们的意见
will persuade you to see our point of view.
- 指挥官 - 是，长官
- Commander. - Yes, sir.
把他们带走
Process them.
上尉，把他们关到四号监狱里
Captain, take them to Camp 4.
收到，收到
Roger, roger.
我们得离开街道，女王陛下
We should leave the street, Your Highness.
拿他们的武器
Get their weapons.
你们真够棒的！
Yousa guys bombad!
我们是最高议会的特使
We're ambassadors for the supreme chancellor.
看来你们的谈判失败了，先生
Your negotiations seemed to have failed, Ambassador.
根本没有开始谈
The negotiations never took place.
我们必须和共和国取得联系
It's urgent that we make contact with the Republic.
通讯全都被他们切断了
They've knocked out all our communications.
- 你们有飞船吗？   - 总机库里有，那边走
- Do you have transports? - In the main hangar. This way.
- 他们人太多了     - 别担心，没问题
- There are too many of them. - That won't be a problem.
女王陛下，在这种情况下
Your Highness, under the circumstances,
我建议请你跟我们到科罗斯肯特星球去
I suggest you come to Coruscant with us.
谢谢特使先生，我要和我的人民在一起
Thank you, Ambassador, but my place is with my people.
- 他们会杀死你的 - 他们不敢
- They will kill you if you stay. - They wouldn't dare.
他们需要女王签署入侵合法化
They need her to sign a treaty to make this invasion legal.
所以不会杀死她的
They can't afford to kill her.
我看他们在背后另有阴谋，女王陛下
There is something else behind all this, Your Highness.
我看他们另有阴谋，入侵行动不合逻辑
There's no logic in the Federation's move here.
我觉得他们是要除掉你们
My feelings tell me they will destroy you.
我们只能期盼国会站在我们一边
Our only hope is for the senate to side with us.
帕尔帕庭议员会需要你们的帮助
Senator Palpatine will need your help.
不管怎样，我们的处境都很危险
Either choice presents great danger... to us all.
我们都会勇敢，女王陛下
We are brave, Your Highness.
如果要走，女王陛下，现在就得走
If you are to leave, Your Highness, it must be now.
我会向国会请求的
Then I will plead our case to the senate.
多加小心，总督
Be careful, Governor.
我们得拯救那些飞行员
We'll need to free those pilots.
让我来吧
I'll deal with that.
站住
Halt.
我是首相的特使
I'm ambassador to the supreme chancellor.
我正在和这些科罗斯肯特人交谈
I'm taking these people to Coruscant.
- 你们要去哪？ - 去科罗斯肯特
- Where are you taking them? - To Coruscant.
科罗斯肯特？这名字无法验测
Coruscant? Uh, that doesn't compute.
嘿，等等，你们被捕了
Uh, wait. Uh, you're under arrest.
快走！
Come on. Move!
走！
Go!
你就待在这儿，不要惹麻烦
Now, stay here and keep out of trouble.
你们好啊，夥计们
Hello, boyos.
是联盟的战舰
There's the blockade.
防护罩起动器被击中了
The shield generator's been hit!
真粗鲁！
How wude!
我们的机械人损失惨重
We're losing droids fast.
没有防护罩，我们就成了活靶子了
If we can't get the shield generator fixed, we'll be sitting ducks.
防护罩没了
The shields are gone.
现在恢复了！
The power's back!
那个小机器人修复了主动力引擎，
That little droid did it. He bypassed the main power drive.
防护罩调到最大
Deflector shields up at maximum.
我们到不了科罗斯肯特了
There's not enough power to get us to Coruscant.
超光速引擎在漏油
The hyperdrive is leaking.
我们先找个地方着陆，修补飞船再加防护
We'll have to land somewhere to refuel and repair the ship.
这儿，师父，塔图因
Here, Master. Tatooine.
这里离航道非常远
It's small, out of the way, poor.
不太可能有贸易联盟的人
The Trade Federation have no presence there.
你怎么这样肯定？
How can you be sure?
这是赫特人的地盘
It's controlled by the Hutts.
在那儿你不能抓他们的女王殿下 赫特人都是匪徒
You can't take Her Royal Highness there. The Hutts are gangsters.
- 如果他们发现她… - 那跟…
- If they discovered her... - It'd be no different than landing...
在贸易联盟控制的星球没什么两样…
on a system controlled by the Federation...
除非赫特人没想要抓她…
except that the Hutts aren't looking for her...
这样给我们优势
which gives us the advantage.
阿米达拉女王在协议上签字了吗？
And Queen Amidala, has she signed the treaty?
她逃跑了，大人
She has disappeared, my lord .
你说纳布星的飞船通过我们的封锁线？
One Naboo cruiser got past the blockade.
我要她签协议
I want that treaty signed.
大人
My lord...
可是我们现在找不到那些飞船
it's impossible to locate the ship.
它飞出了我们的探侧范围
It's out of our range.
西斯人可以
Not for a Sith.
这是我的徒弟
This is my apprentice...
达斯・摩尔
Darth Maul.
他会帮助你找那艘飞船的
He will find your lost ship.
现在更麻烦了
This is getting out of hand.
又来了一个君主
Now there are two of them.
我们不听他的就好了
We should not have made this bargain.
多亏了这个精巧的机器人，女王陛下
An extremely well-put-together little droid, Your Highness.
它救了飞船，也救了我们大家的命
Without a doubt, it saved the ship, as well as our lives.
我要奖赏他，他的号码是多少？
It is to be commended. What is its number?
是R2D2，女王陛下
R2-D2, Your Highness.
谢谢你，R2D2
Thank you, R2-D2.
帕德梅
Padme
好好给他清洗一下
Clean this droid up as best you can.
我们应该感谢他
It deserves our gratitude.
接着说吧，船长
Continue, Captain.
女王陛下，请允许…
Your Highness, with your permission...
我们现在正飞往一个叫塔普尼的遥远的星球
we're heading for a remote planet called Tatooine.
那是贸易联盟势力之外的星球
It's in a system far beyond the reach of the Trade Federation.
可我不同意到那个星球去
I do not agree with the Jedi on this.
请相信我的判断，女王陛下
You must trust my judgment, Your Highness.
你好
Hello.
对不起，能问问你是谁吗？
Sorry. Husa are yousa?
我叫帕德梅
I'm Padme
我叫加加宾可斯
Mesa JarJar Binks.
你是冈根人？
You're a Gungan, aren't you?
- 那你怎么跑到这儿来了？ - 我也不知道
- How'd you end up here with us? - My no know.
今天早晨，我正高高兴兴的吃早饭
Mesa day starten pitty okeyday witda brisky morning munchen.
突然，砰的一声吓坏我了
Den boom! Getten berry scared...
那个绝地武士就救了我一命
and grabben dat Jedi, and pow... mesa here.
你知道吗？我非常非常害怕
Mesa getten berry, berry scared.
- 那就是… 塔图因星球 - 那是一个市镇
- That's it... Tatooine. - There's a settlement.
着陆时离市镇远一点，不要引起人们的注意
Land near the outskirts. We don't want to attract attention.
超光速已经失灵了，得换个新的
The hyperdrive generator's gone, Master. We'll need a new one.
情况很棘手，要小心
That'll complicate things. Be wary.
- 我感到原力受到干扰了 - 我也感觉到了，师父
- I sense a disturbance in the Force. - I feel it also, Master.
要他们别再传输信息了
Don't let them send any transmissions.
噢，这太阳真的是　死人了
The sun doen murder to mesa skin.
等一下
Wait!
Wait.
女王陛下命令你们带上她的女仆
Her Highness commands you to take her handmaiden with you.
女王今天就别再发布命令了，船长
No more commands from Her Highness today, Captain.
这个太空站很危险
The spaceport is not going to be pleasant.
这是女王的意思
The queen wishes it.
她对这个星球很好奇
She's curious about the planet.
真拿她没办法 不要离我太远
This is not a good idea. Stay close to me.
湿气农场，是主要部分
Moisture farms, for the most part.
住的一些本土部落和一些外来定居的人
Some indigenous tribes and scavengers.
像这种偏远的太空站…
The few spaceports like this one...
是那些不希望被找到人的天堂
are havens for those that don't wish to be found.
就像我们
Like us.
这也太糟糕了
Dissen berry, berry bad.
这什么破路啊！
Icky, icky goo!
去一家小一点的店
We'll try one of the smaller dealers.
你们好啊
Good day to you.
想买点什么？
What do you want?
有没有J型327雷比亚飞船的零件
I need parts for a J-type 327 Nubian.
有，雷比亚！有的是
Ah, yes! Nubian. We have lots of that.
孩子，起来吧
Boy, get in here now!
我的机械人有我所需要的零件清单
My droid has a readout of what I need.
怎么耽搁这么久啊？
What took you so long?
我在擦风扇的开关
I was cleaning the fan switches.
看着铺子，我有笔生意要做
Watch the store. I've got some selling to do.
先生，咱们到后面去吧？
So, let me take thee out back, huh?
那儿有你需要的东西
We'll find what you need.
什么也不要碰
Don't touch anything.
- 你是个天使吗？ - 什么？
- Are you an angel? - What?
天使，我听外太空飞行员说起过天使
An angel. I heard the deep space pilots talk about them.
他们是宇宙中最漂亮的动物
They're the most beautiful creatures in the universe.
他们住在伊国月球上，我想是的
They live on the moons of Iego, I think.
你这个孩子真有意思 你怎么知道那么多？
You're a funny little boy. How do you know so much?
我是听路过这的商贩和星际飞行员说的
I listen to all the traders and star pilots who come through here.
我是飞行员，你知道吗，总有一天
I'm a pilot, you know, and someday
我会飞出这个地方的
I'm gonna fly away from this place.
- 你是飞行员？ - 当了一辈子了
- You're a pilot? - Mm-hmm. All my life.
你来这里多久了？
How long have you been here?
小时候就来了，大概三岁吧
Since I was very little. Three, I think.
我和我妈妈被卖给赫特人歌杜拿，
My mom and I were sold to Gardulla the Hutt...
在飞行比赛中他把我们输给了别人
but she lost us betting on the Podraces.
你是奴隶？
You're a slave?
- 我是个人，我的名字是安纳金 - 对不起
- I'm a person, and my name is Anakin. - I'm sorry.
我还是不太明白，这个地方对我来说太奇怪了
I don't fully understand. This is a strange place to me.
你要去哪？
Where... Wheres yousa goin?
我拿到了
I got ya.
什么？敲它的鼻子
Hit the nose.
你要的是T-14超光速引擎，你真走运
A T-1 4 hyperdrive generator. Thee in luck.
这东西只有我这里有
I'm the only one hereabouts who has one.
不过你还是买艘新飞船那样更合算
But thee might as well buy a new ship. It would be cheaper, I think, huh.
说到这个…
Saying of which...
你打算怎样付款呢？
how's thee gonna pay for all this, huh?
我有两万的共和国信用额
I have 20,000 Republic dataries.
共和国信用？
Republic credits?
共和国的信贷在这里不通用，我要比较实在的
Republic credits are no good out here. I need something more real.
我没有其它东西了，但信用是可用的
I don't have anything else, but credits will do fine.
- 不，那不行  - 信用可用
- No, they won't. - Credits will do fine.
不，信用不行！
No, they won't!
你以为你是绝地武士吗？
What, you think you're some kind of Jedi,
就像这样子挥挥手吗？
waving your hand around like that?
我可是陶达人，心灵控制对我无效，我要现金
I'm a Toydarian. Mind tricks don't work on me. Only money.
没钱，就没零件，没交易
No money, no parts, no deal.
我可告诉你这没有人有P-14引擎了
And no one else has a T-1 4 hyperdrive, I promise you that.
我能够生存这么久
Wouldn't have lasted long anyways
是因为我精于手艺
if I wasn't so good at building things.
我们走吧，加加
We're leaving. JarJar.
认识你很高兴，安纳金
I'm glad to have met you, Anakin.
认识你我也很高兴
I was glad to meet you too.
噢，哪儿去了？
What? Wha... Oh.
外来人，他们以为我们什么都不懂
Outlanders. They think we know nothing.
他们对我挺好的
They seemed nice to me.
清洗货架，
Clean the racks.
然后就回家吧
Then you can go home.
Yippee!
飞船上有没有贵重物品？
And you're sure there 's nothing left on board?
飞船上有些食粮补给
A few containers of supplies.
女王的外衣也许值钱，但肯定不够交易…
The queen's ward robe, maybe, but not enough for you to barter with...
那个引擎所需的金额数量
not in the amount you're talking about.
好吧，没关系，我相信一定会有别的办法
All right. I'm sure another solution will present itself.
我一会再跟你联系
I'll check back later.
不能去，不能去
Noah gain. Noah gain.
这里的人都是疯子
Da beings hereabouts, cawazy!
他们会抢劫我们的
Wesa be wobbed un crunched.
不会的，我们没有什么值钱的东西，这就是我们的问题
Not likely. We have nothing of value. That's our problem.
你打算要付钱？
Are you going to pay for that?
他值7个乌比奥(货币)
It costs seven wupiupi.
Oops.
这是你的吗？
Is this yours?
是谁的…
Who, mesa...
当心呀，泽布巴
Careful, Sebulba.
他可是个厉害的外星人
He's a big-time outlander.
在比赛之前我可不想见到你送命
I'd hate to see you diced before we race again.
下一次我们比赛的时候，小子，你就要完蛋了
Next time we race, boy, it will be the end of you.
你要不是个奴隶，我早就宰了你了
If you weren't a slave, I'd squash you now.
是啊，那么遗憾的是你就得为我的命赔钱了
Yeah, it'd be a pity if you had to pay for me.
- 你好 - 你好吗
- Hi. - Hi there.
你的朋友差点变成了烂桔子了
Your buddy here was about to be turned into orange goo.
他挑起了一场争斗，和一个德格人…
He picked a fight with a Dug...
一个特别危险的德格人，叫泽布巴
an especially dangerous Dug called Sebulba.
我不喜欢打架，能不打还是不打的好
Mesa haten crunchen. Das da las ting mesa want.
虽然这样，这小子是对的，你没少惹麻烦
Nevertheless, the boy is right. You were heading into trouble.
谢谢你，我的小朋友
Thanks, my young friend.
但是… 但是…
But... But...
可我没做什么错事啊！
But mesa doen nutten!
沙暴会减慢他们的速度
This storm will slow them down.
真糟糕
Looks pretty bad.
- 什么事？ - 收到总部的消息
- Panaka. - Receiving a message from home.
我们会等着的
We'll be right there.
给你，你会喜欢这些水果的
Here, you'll like these pallies.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
噢，我的骨头又疼了
My bones are aching.
沙暴马上就要来了，快点回家吧
Storm's coming up, Ani. You better get home quick.
- 你们有防风的地方吗？ - 我们回飞船去
- Do you have shelter? - We'll head back to our ship.
- 远不远？   - 在市镇外面
- Is it far? - It's on the outskirts.
你们没时间赶回飞船了
You'll never reach the outskirts in time.
沙风暴要来了，是非常非常危险的
Sandstorms are very, very dangerous.
来吧，我带你们去我们家
Come on. I'll take you to my place.
妈妈！
Mom!
- 妈妈，我回来了！ - 噢，这真舒服
- Mom, I'm home! - Ah, dissen cosy.
- 他们是我的朋友，妈妈 - 你好
- These are my friends, Mom. - Hello.
- 我叫奎刚・金 - 我正在制造一个机器人，要看看吗？
- I'm Qui-Gon Jinn. - I'm building a droid. You wanna see?
是你儿子让我们来这儿躲避沙暴的
Your son was kind enough to offer us shelter.
来呀，看看我的3PO
Come on. I'll show you 3PO.
怎么样，不错吧？我还没做完呢
Isn't he great? He's not finished yet.
真是太棒了
He's wonderful.
你真的喜欢？
You really like him?
他是公关机器人，能帮助妈妈，你看
He's a protocol droid to help Mom. Watch.
人都哪儿去了？
Where is everybody?
Whoops.
你好
Oh, hello.
你好，我是C-3PO，公关机器人
I am C-3PO, human cyborg relations.
愿意为你效劳？
How might I serve you?
- 他太完美了 - 完美？
- He's perfect. - Oh. Perfect.
等沙暴过去了，我带你去看看我的赛艇，是我制作的
When the storm is over, I'll show you my racer. I'm building a Podracer.
这个地方好像有些不平
I'm not sure this floor is entirely stable.
你好， 我们好像没有见过面的
Hello. I don't believe we have been introduced.
R2-D2，很高兴认识你
R2-D2. A pleasure to meet you.
我是C-3PO，公关机器人
I am C-3PO, human cyborg relations.
对不起，你说'赤裸'？'赤裸'是什么意思？
I beg your pardon, but what do you mean, "naked"?
我的内部零件裸露？ 我的上帝！
My parts are showing? My goodness!
纳布星的人民死伤惨重
The death toll is catastrophic.
我们还是让步吧
We must bow to their wishes.
你们必须和我联系
You must contact me.
是个圈套，不要回覆
It's a trick. Send no reply.
什么信息也不要发过去
Send no transmissions of any kind.
他们想利用通讯信号来确定我们的位置
It sounds like bait to establish a connection trace.
如果是真的呢？ 真的死伤惨重呢？
What if it is true, and the people are dying?
我们的时间不多了
Either way, we're running out of time.
塔普尼是人口稀疏
Tatooine is sparsely populated.
如果位置正确，定能找到他们
If the trace was correct, I will find them quickly, Master.
先对付绝地武士
Move against the Jedi first.
到时候你就轻而易举地把女王带到纳布星来…
You will then have no difficulty in taking the queen to Naboo...
签署协议了
to sign the treaty.
我们终于可以向绝地武士显露身份了
At last we will reveal ourselves to the Jedi.
可以有机会报仇了
At last we will have revenge.
你已经训练有素了，我的小徒弟
You have been well-trained, my young apprentice.
他们不是你的对手
They will be no match for you.
他们在每一个奴隶的体内都安装了一个发射器
All slaves have a transmitter placed inside their bodies somewhere.
我想做一个扫描器把我的发射器找出来
I've been working on a scanner to try and locate mine.
- 要是逃跑的话… - 就会被发射器炸死！
- Any attempt to escape... - And they blow you up!
太没礼貌了！
How wude!
真没想到银河系还有奴隶制
I can't believe there's still slavery in the galaxy.
共和国有反奴隶法啊…
The Republic's antislavery laws...
共和国管不到我们这儿
The Republic doesn't exist out here.
我们要生存就得靠自己
We must survive on our own.
对不起
Xcuse me.
你们有谁看过飞艇赛吗？
Has anybody ever seen a Podrace?
马拉斯代尔星球有飞艇赛
They have Podracing on Malastare.
速度很快，非常危险
Very fast, very dangerous.
我是唯一能开的人类
I'm the only human who can do it.
那你得有绝地武士的反应速度才行
You must have Jedi reflexes if you race pods.
别这么吃东西
Don't do that again.
你是个绝地武士，对吧？
You're a Jedi knight, aren't you?
- 你怎么知道的？ - 我看见你的激光剑了
- What makes you think that? - I saw your laser sword.
只有绝地武士才有这种武器
Only Jedis carry that kind of weapon.
那也许我是杀了绝地武士缴获的呢
Perhaps I killed a Jedi and took it from him.
那是不可能的
I don't think so.
没有人能杀得了绝地武士
No one can kill a Jedi.
但愿你说的是对的
I wish that were so.
有一次我梦见我自己成了绝地武士
I had a dream I was a Jedi.
回来解放所有的奴隶
I came back here and freed all the slaves.
- 你们是来解放我们的吗？ - 不，很遗憾
- Have you come to free us? - No, I'm afraid not.
我觉得你们是 要不然你们来这儿干什么？
I think you have. Why else would you be here?
我并不想欺骗你啊，安纳金
I can see there's no fooling you, Anakin.
我们是要到银河系的首府
We're on our way to Coruscant, the central system in the Republic...
科斯肯特去执行一项重要任务
on a very important mission.
那你们怎么跑到银河系的外围来了？
How did you end up out here in the outer rim?
我们的飞船坏了，这里好修理飞船
Our ship was damaged, and we're stranded here until we can repair it.
我能帮你们，我什么都会修
I can help. I can fix anything.
我相信你会
I believe you can.
可是我们得需要搞到所需要的零件
But first we must acquire the parts we need.
但是我们又没钱去买
Wit no-nutten mula to trade.
那些小商贩一定有某些弱点，我们可以利用
These junk dealers must have a weakness of some kind.
赌博，他们为了赛艇比赛什么东西都愿意赌
Gambling. Everything here revolves around betting on those awful races.
飞梭赛车
Podracing.
我们可以利用他们的贪心
Greed can be a powerful ally.
我造的飞艇是速度最快的
I built a racer. It's the fastest ever.
明天嘣嗒前夕有场大赛
There's a big race tomorrow on Boonta Eve.
你们帮我报名吧
You could enter my pod.
安纳金，瓦图不会同意的
Anakin, Watto won't let you.
瓦图不知道我造了赛艇
Watto doesn't know I've built it.
就说是你们的赛艇
You could make him think it was yours...
想办法让他们允许我开就行了
and get him to let me pilot it for you.
我不想让你去，那太可怕了
I don't want you to race. It's awful.
每次瓦图让你比赛都让我担心死了
I die every time Watto makes you do it.
可是妈妈，我非常喜欢
But, Mom, I love it.
再说赢了奖金还可以帮他们买零件
The prize money would more than pay for the parts they need.
安纳金，
Anakin.
你妈妈是对的
Your mother's right.
有谁对共和国比较友好可以帮助我们的吗？
Is there anyone friendly to the Republic who can help us?
.没有
No.
妈妈，你不是说宇宙中最大的问题
Mom, you say the biggest problem in this universe
就是人们不互相帮助吗？
is nobody helps each other.
奎刚他是不想让你的儿子去冒险
I'm sure Qui-Gon doesn't want to put your son in danger.
我们会另想办法的
We'll find some other way.
不，没有别的办法
There is no other way.
虽然我不愿意让他去，可他能帮助你们
I may not like it, but he can help you.
他注定是要帮助你们的
He was meant to help you.
你真想这么干吗？
Are you sure about this?
把我们的命运寄托在一个孩子身上
Trusting our fate to a boy we hardly know?
女王是不会同意的
The queen will not approve.
没必要让女王知道
The queen doesn't need to know.
我也不同意
Well, I don't approve.
这孩子说你们要资助他参加比赛
The boy tells me you want to sponsor him in the race.
你们用什么资助？
How can you do this?
不会是用共和国信贷吧？
Not on the Republic credits, I think.
我用我的飞船作抵压，作参赛费
My ship will be the entry fee.
不错，不错
Not bad!
一艘露比亚？
Not bad, huh? Nubian, huh?
飞船状况良好，只是缺一点零件
It's in good order, except for the parts I need.
那孩子会驾驶什么呢？
What would the boy ride?
上次比赛，他把我的飞艇撞毁了
He smashed up my pod in the last race.
得需要较长一段时间来修好它
It would take some long time to fix it.
那不能怪我，真的
It wasn't my fault. Really.
是泽布巴用他的排气管袭击我
Sebulba flashed me with his vents.
其实还是我保住了飞艇，大部分的
I actually saved the pod, mostly.
你保住的
That you did.
这孩子的身手的确不错
The boy's good. No doubts there, huh?
我在一次赛事中赢了一艘飞船
I have acquired a pod in a game of chance.
是速度最快的
The fastest ever built.
但愿你不是杀人越货抢来的吧？
I hope you didn't kill anyone I know for it, huh?
好，你提供飞艇和参赛费…
So, you supply the pod and the entry fee...
我提供这孩子
and I supply the boy.
赢了钱五五分怎么样？
We split the winnings 50-50, I think, huh?
如果说五五分的话…
If it's going to be 50-50...
那参赛费得由你来预支
I suggest you front the cash for the entry.
如果我们赢了…
If we win...
奖金都归你，你给我零件就行了
you keep all the winnings, minus the cost of the parts I need.
要是我们输了的话，我的飞艇归你
And if we lose, you keep my ship.
怎么你都合算
Either way, you win.
说定了！
Deal!
我看你的朋友是个大傻瓜
Your friend is a foolish one, methinks.
师父，要是计划失败了呢？
What if this plan fails, Master?
那我们就困在这里，走不了啦
We could be stuck here a very long time.
现在发求救信息太危险了
Well, it 's too dangerous to call for help...
没有动力的飞船根本没用，
and a ship without a power supply isn't going to get us anywhere.
再说
And...
这个孩子很特别
there's something about this boy.
真该为你的儿子感到骄傲
You should be very proud of your son.
他施予，但不求回报
He gives without any thought of reward .
心里毫无贪念
He knows nothing of greed.
他有…
He has...
他有超常的能力
He has special powers.
是的
Yes.
他能预知将要发生的事情
He can see things before they happen.
所以他的反应很快，
That's why he appears to have such quick reflexes.
这种特徵是绝地武士的
It's a Jedi trait.
他不该过奴隶的生活
He deserves better than a slave's life.
要是他出生在共和国
Had he been born in the Republic,
我们可以早点定位他
we would have identified him early.
他身上的生命原力很强，也很清晰
The Force is unusually strong with him. That much is clear.
他父亲是谁？
Who was his father?
他没有父亲
There was no father.
我怀了他，生了他，抚养他…
I carried him, I gave birth, I raised him.
我也解释不清楚，我怎么怀上他的
I can't explain what happened.
能帮他吗？
Can you help him?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我不是来解救奴隶的
I didn't actually come here to free slaves.
哗，是工程机器人
Wow, a real astro droid!
- 你怎么这么幸运？  - 这算什么呀
- How do you get so lucky? - That isn't the half of it.
- 我还要参加邦塔大赛呢 - 什么？
- I'm in the Boonta race tomorrow. - What?
用这个？
With this?
你真会开玩笑，安
You're such a joker, Ani.
- 这个你造了好几年了  - 它跑不起来
- You've been working on that for years. - It's never gonna run.
走，咱们去打球吧
Come on. Let's go and play ball.
你好好比赛吧，安 你会被压扁的
Keep racing, Ani. You're gonna be bug squash.
别碰那个动力电流夹
Keep away from those energy binders.
手要是碰到了那个电流，会麻木好几个小时的
If your hand gets caught in the beam, it's gonna go numb for hours.
好的
Okay.
我的舌头太肥了
My tongue is fat.
我的舌头… 扳手
My tongue... Wrench.
扳手丢哪儿了？哦，竟敢这样
Where is de wrench? Oh, dare it is.
被夹住了
I'm stuck.
你知道吗，我觉得加加这家伙有点奇怪啊
You know, I find that JarJar creature to be a little odd.
你都不知道它能不能跑起来
You don't even know if this thing's gonna run.
- 它能跑  - 我想是时候试一试了
- It will. - I think it's time we found out.
- 给你，用这个充电 - 好的，先生！
- Here, use this power charge. - Yes, sir!
起来，克斯特，我们让开
Come on, Kitster. Let's move away.
我的嘴
My mouth.
安，我卡住了
Ani, I'm stuck.
我舌头卡住了
My tongue is fat.
你说得对，他很奇怪
You're quite right. He's very odd indeed.
谢谢
Thank you.
走
Go.
发动了！发动了！
It's working! It's working!
坐好别动，我帮你清理伤口
Stay still, Ani. Let me clean this cut.
这么多星星，每个星星都有行星组成的星系吗？
There's so many. Do they all have a system of planets?
多数都有
Most of them.
有人去过所有星球吗？
Has anyone been to'em all?
好像没有
Not likely.
我要成为第一个人
I wanna be the first one to see 'em all.
安，该睡觉了！
Ani, bedtime!
好了，没问题了
There we are. Good as new.
安，你听见了没有
Ani, I'm not gonna tell you again.
- 这是干什么？ - 它看你的血液有没有感染
- What are you doing? - Checking your blood for infections.
去睡吧
Go on.
明天有你忙的
You have a big day tomorrow.
睡个好觉
Sleep well, Ani.
- 欧比旺？ - 是，师父？
- Obi-Wan? - Yes, Master?
我发送过去一个血样，你分析一下
I need an analysis of this blood sample I'm sending you.
稍等
Wait a minute.
midi-chlorian的读数是多少？
I need a midi-chlorian count.
读数非常高
The reading is off the chart.
已经大大超过了两万
Over 20,000.
尤达师父也没有这么高的读数…
Even Master Yoda doesn't have a midi-chlorian count that high.
绝地武士都没有这么高
No Jedi has.
这意味着什么？
What does that mean?
还不太清楚
I'm not sure.
比赛以前我就想看看你的飞船
I wanna see your spaceship the moment the race is over.
耐心点，我蓝色的朋友
Patience, my blue friend.
日落之前你会看到奖金
You'll have your winnings before the suns set.
我们也可以离开这里了
And we'll be far away from here.
要不就你那可爱的飞艇归我？
Not if your ship belongs to me, I think, huh?
我警告你，别玩花样
I warn you, no funny business.
- 你觉得安纳金赢不了吗？ - 别误解我的信息
- You don't think Anakin can win? - Don't get me wrongo.
我对那孩子很有信心
I have great faith in the boy.
他会为你们赢得荣誉…
He's a credit to your race...
不过我看还是萨布巴能赢
but Sebulba there is going to win, I think.
哦，不！
Oh, no!
你怎么会这么想的？
Why do you think that?
他总是赢！
He always wins!
我把赌注都押在泽布巴身上
I am betting heavily on Sebulba.
- 那我跟你赌 - 什么？
- I'll take that bet. - What?
我以我的新赛艇跟你赌，就用…
I'll wager my new racing pod against, say...
那孩子和他妈妈
the boy and his mother.
赛艇哪能值两个奴隶，绝对不行
No pod is worth two slaves, not by a long shot.
只赌那个孩子呢？
The boy, then.
那就让运气来决定吧
We'll let fate decide, huh?
这么巧，我这刚好带了一粒骰子
I just happen to have a chance cube here.
蓝色，是那孩子
Blue, it's the boy.
红色是…
Red...
他的妈妈
his mother.
这次掷骰子你赢了，异乡人…
You won this small toss, outlander...
但你是赢不了比赛的！
but you won't win the race!
所以这没差别！
So it makes little difference!
最好劝劝你的朋友别赌了，不然他可要输惨了
Better stop your friend's betting or I'll end up owning him too.
- 他这话什么意思？ - 待会告诉你
- What'd he mean by that? - I'll tell you later.
早上好
Good morning.
天哪，太空旅行听起来太危险了
Oh, my. Space travel sounds rather perilous.
跟你们说吧
I can assure you,
他们别想把我弄上那些可怕的飞船
they will never get me onto one of those dreadful starships.
真是奇才，安 我确信这次你会做到的
This is so wizard, Ani. I'm sure you'll do it this time.
做什么？
Do what?
当然是完成这次比赛啦
Finish the race, of course.
你从来没有赢过比赛？
You've never won a race?
我是没赢过
Well, not exactly.
甚至没有跑完全程？
Not even finished?
克斯特说的没错 这次我会跑完全程
Kitster's right. I will this time.
你当然能行
Of course you will.
极速飞梭大赛
Podracers.
那可是绝对正确
That's absolutely right.
很多来自银河系边缘的高手会聚到这里
And a big turnout here from all corners of the outer rim territories.
我看见比赛选手移动到他们的起跑线
I see the contestants are making their way out onto the starting grid.
我看见来自通德星系的本・奎迪纳斯
Isee Ben Quadinaros from the Tund System.
还有两界冠军获得者博尔斯・威尔
Two-time winner Boles Roor.
泽布巴！
Sebulba!
在前一排，靠近起跑位置的是…
And in the front row, nearside pole position...
马・霍力克！
Ma whonic!
隆重介绍…
A hearty hello...
克莱格・霍法斯特和他的KT9飞艇！
to Clegg Holdfast and his Voltec KT9 Wasp!
再往后，是伟大的达德・波特…
And back again, it's the mighty Dud Bolt...
和他那非凡的座驾，Vulptereen 327
with that incredible racing machine, the Vulptereen 327.
有望成为今天的赢家是…
And hoping for a big win today...
欧迪・曼德瑞尔，他曾取得过非凡的战绩
Ody Mandrell, with his record-setting pit droid team.
还有最后参赛的年轻的安纳金・天行者…
And a late entry, young Anakin Skywalker...
一个本地小子
a local boy.
发令员正进入跑道
I see the flags are moving out onto the track.
它放屁了！
Pee yousa!
小心点
Be safe.
我会赢的，妈妈，我答应你
I will, Mom. I promise.
这次你死定了…
You won't walk away from this one...
你这个小奴隶
you slave scum.
你就等着瞧吧，烂泥球
Don't count on it, slime ball.
你会死无葬身之地的！
You're bantha fodder!
- 准备好了吗？ - 好了
- You all set, Ani? - Yep.
好了，来
Right.
记住，要集中精神
Remember, concentrate on the moment.
凭感觉，别思考，利用本能的力量
Feel, don't think. Use your instincts.
我会的
I will.
原力与你同在
May the Force be with you.
赫特人贾巴
Jabba the Hutt.
欢迎大家
Welcome.
我宣布比赛开始！
Begin the race!
看起来他们已经各就各位了
Hey, looks like they're clearing the grid.
- 他紧张吗？ - 他没事
- Is he nervous? - He's fine.
你们绝地武士太鲁莽了，女王是不…
You Jedi are far too reckless. The queen is not...
女王她信任我，年轻的女仆
The queen trusts my judgment, young handmaiden.
你也该信任我
You should too.
你太自以为是了
You assume too much.
发动引擎
Start your engines.
噢，肯定会撞得一塔糊涂，我看不下去了！
Oh, dissen gonna be messy. Me no watch'n!
糟了！
Oh, no!
不好，天行者的飞艇动不了啦
Wait. Little Skywalker has stalled.
奎迪纳斯的引擎好像也出了问题
It looks like Quadinaros is having engine trouble also.
加油啊，安
Come on, Ani!
天行者飞起来了！
And there goes Skywalker!
加油，安，加油！
Go, Ani, go!
他得奋力而行才能追上前面的飞艇
He will be hard-pressed to catch up with the leaders.
好像一帮塔斯肯袭击者驻扎在…
Looks like a few Tusken Raiders are camped out...
峡谷拐弯角处
on the canyon dune turn.
什么破东西！
Doowat macroon!
奎迪纳斯的引擎给炸毁了
There goes Quadinaros' power coupling.
Cheespa wata!
Ooh!
Chubba ni chees Sebulba! Paketa!
Kulkah meeka!
Ody Mandrell coona wa wunda dungo!
哦，不！
Oh, no!
安纳金，师父在哪儿？
Where is Master Anakin?
看，他来了
Look. Here he comes.
天行者飞越了主赛场
It looks like Skywalker is moving up in the field.
Yay! Yippee!
让他再跑两圈吧？天哪！
He has to complete two more circuits? Oh, dear.
Arrr!
天行者引擎失控了
Skywalker's spinning out of control!
不管你来自哪个星球，这一摔一定也够受的！
I don't care what universe you're from. That's gotta hurt!
他来了！
Here he comes!
在第三也是最后一圈的开始，萨布巴领先…
At the start of the third and final lap, Sebulba's in the lead...
天行者紧随其后！
followed closely by Skywalker!
加油，安！
Go, Ani!
天行者要撞到服务站了！
Skywalker's been forced onto the service ramp!
Huh？
是天行者！
It's Skywalker!
萨布巴！
Sebulba!
太精彩了！真精准的控制，他又飞回跑道上了！
Amazing! A quick control thrust, and he's back on course!
他撞死了吗？
Did he crash-ed?
天行者有麻烦了！泽布巴领先！
Skywalker's in trouble! Sebulba takes the lead!
- 他在追赶泽布巴！ - 看来要追上了！
- He's catching Sebulba! - Inkabunga!
当心，安，当心，安！
Careful, Ani. Careful, Ani!
Wha-- Chuba da noya！
这个人类的小孩真是疯了！
That little human being is out of his mind!
- 他们并排飞行！ - 不相上下！
- They're side by side! - Bangu du bangu!
Aaah!
Poo doo!
- Yippee! - Yay!
Ya eeka buta!
真是难以置信
I can't believe it.
观众都沸腾了！
The crowds are going nuts!
好，安！
Yay, Ani!
妈妈，我成功了！
Mom, I did it! Yay!
你真棒，安！
Good going, Ani!
你救了我们，安
We owe you everything, Ani.
真是太好了，安
It's so wonderful, Ani.
你给我们奴隶带来了希望
You have brought hope to those who have none.
我真为你感到骄傲
I'm so very proud of you.
库巴，不
Oy chuba no.
你！
You!
你骗了我
You swindled me.
你早知道那孩子能赢，你肯定知道
You knew the boy was going to win. Somehow you knew it.
我现在什么都没有了
I lost everything.
只要你赌博，我的朋友，你就早晚会输
Whenever you gamble, my friend, eventually you lose.
把零件送到飞船那儿去
Bring the parts to the main hangar.
我等一会儿到店里去带走那孩子
I'll come by your shop later on so you can release the boy.
你不能把他带走，这是一个不公平赌博
You can't have him. It wasn't a fair bet.
你想去赫特人那儿去讲理吗？
Would you like to discuss it with the Hutts?
我想他们会处理此事的
I'm sure they can settle this.
带他走吧
Take him.
你好！
Hidoe!
好了，我们拿到所需要的零件了
Well, we have all the essential parts we need.
马上回来
I'm going back.
还有一些未完成的事情 我不会待太久
Some unfinished business. I won't be long.
我怎么感觉到我们又要带上一个可怜的人了？
Why do I sense we've picked up another pathetic life-form?
是那个帮我们弄到零件的孩子
It's the boy who's responsible for getting us these parts.
快把超光影速引擎装上吧
Get this hyperdrive generator installed.
是，师父，不要多长时间的
Yes, Master. That shouldn't take long.
来吧
Come on. Hup!
这些是你的
Hey. These are yours.
好！
Yes!
妈妈，我们把飞艇卖了！看看咱们有多少钱！
Mom, we sold the pod! Look at all the money we have!
天哪！那真是太好了，安
My goodness! But that's so wonderful, Ani.
- 而且他成自由之身了 - 什么？
- And he has been freed. - What?
你不再是奴隶了
You're no longer a slave.
你听到了吗？
Did you hear that?
现在你能去实现你自己的梦想了，安
Now you can make your dreams come true, Ani.
你自由了
You are free.
你把他带走吗？
Will you take him with you?
他会成会绝地武士吗？
Is he to become a Jedi?
是的，我们相会并非是偶然的
Yes. Our meeting was not a coincidence.
什么事都不是偶然发生的
Nothing happens by accident.
你是说我可以跟你坐飞船离开这里吗？
You mean I get to come with you in your starship?
安纳金…
Anakin...
要成为绝地武士并不是容易的事
training to become a Jedi is not an easy challenge...
绝地武士的生活是十分艰难的
and even if you succeed, it's a hard life.
但是我想去，我一直梦想成为绝地武士
But I wanna go. It's what I've always dreamed of doing.
我能去吗？
Can I go, Mom?
安纳金…
Anakin...
生活的道路已经在你脚下了
this path has been placed before you.
应该由你自己决定
The choice is yours alone.
我要去
I wanna do it.
那就收拾好东西，我们的时间不多了
Then pack your things. We haven't much time.
太好了！
Yippee!
那妈妈呢？
What about Mom?
她也自由了吗？
Is she free too?
我也想解救你妈妈，可瓦图不同意
I tried to free your mother, Ani, but Watto wouldn't have it.
你也和我们一起走吧，妈妈？
You're coming with us, aren't you, Mom?
孩子，我只能留下，这是我的归宿
Son, my place is here. My future is here.
是时候让你走了
It is time for you to let go.
我不想就这么离开你
I don't want things to change.
可这是命中注定的
But you can't stop the change...
你改变不了就像太阳要落山一样
any more than you can stop the suns from setting.
我爱你
I love you.
好了，快走吧
Now hurry.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我会照顾他的，你放心吧
I'll watch after him. You have my word .
你不会有事吧？
Will you be all right?
不会
Yeah.
你好，安纳金主人
Hello, Master Anakin.
C-3PO，我自由了…
Well, 3PO, I've been freed...
我要坐飞船离开这儿了
and I'm going away in a starship.
安纳金主人，你造了我，我祝你平安
Master Anakin, you are my maker and I wish you well.
不过我真希望你能给我装个外壳
However, I should prefer it if I were a little more completed.
对不起，我没能把你做完，3PO…
I'm sorry I wasn't able to finish you, 3PO...
本该给你装外壳的
give you coverings and all.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss working on you.
你是个了不起的朋友
You've been a great pal.
我会告诉妈妈别把你卖掉
I'll make sure Mom doesn't sell you or anything.
卖掉我？
Sell me?
再见
Bye.
天哪
Oh, my.
我不能走，妈妈，我真的不能
I can't do it, Mom. I just can't do it.
安
Ani.
我还能见到你吗？
Will I ever see you again?
你的内心怎么说的？
What does your heart tell you?
但愿能
I hope so.
能
Yes.
我想能
I guess.
那我们就会再见面的
Then we will see each other again.
我会回来解救你的，妈妈
I will come back and free you, Mom.
我保证
I promise.
好了，勇敢些…
Now, be brave...
别回头看我
and don't look back.
不要回头看我
Don't look back.
奎刚先生，等等！
Qui-Gon, sir, wait!
- 我累了！ - 安纳金！趴下！
- I'm tired! - Anakin! Drop!
快跑！
Go!
告诉他们起飞！
Tell them to take off!
奎刚有麻烦了
Qui-Gon's in trouble.
起飞
Take off.
在那儿，飞低点
Over there. Fly low.
- 你没受伤吧？ - 好像没有
- Are you all right? - I think so.
是什么人？
What was it?
还不清楚…
I'm not sure...
不过他精通绝地技艺
but it was well-trained in the Jedi arts.
好像是来抓女王的
My guess is it was after the queen.
那我们该怎么办呢？
What are we gonna do about it?
我们得耐心点
We shall be patient.
安尼金・天行者…
Anakin Skywalker...
认识一下欧比旺・肯诺比
meet Obi-Wan Kenobi.
你好
Hi.
你也是绝地武士？很高兴认识你
You're a Jedi too? Pleased to meet you.
你们的女王不见了，你们的人民在挨饿…
Your queen is lost, your people are starving...
而你，执政官，你会死…
and you, Governor, are going to die...
在你们的人民之前，我害怕是
much sooner than your people, I'm afraid.
你们入侵不会得逞
This invasion will gain you nothing.
我们是民主星球，一切由人民决定
We're a democracy. The people have decided.
把他带走
Take him away.
我的军队正在开始搜索沼泽里…
My troops are in position to begin searching the swamps...
那些传说中的水下村庄
for these rumoured underwater villages.
他们藏不了多久了
They will not stay hidden for long.
我们的人民死伤惨重
The death toll is catastrophic.
我们还是让步吧
We must bow to their wishes.
你们必须跟我取得联系
You must contact me.
你怎么啦？
You all right?
我特别冷
It's very cold.
你来自一个温暖的星球，安
You come from a warm planet, Ani.
对于我来说太温暖了
A little too warm for my taste.
太空是冷的
Space is cold.
你不太高兴
You seem sad.
女王很着急
The queen is worried.
.她的人民正面临死亡的威胁
Her people are suffering, dying.
她必须说服国会出面干涉
She must convince the senate to intervene or...
还不知道能不能成功
I'm not sure what'll happen.
这是我为你做的…
I made this for you...
希望你能记住我
so you'd remember me.
是我用甲板木刻的
I carved it out of a japor snippet.
它会给你带来好运的
It'll bring you good fortune.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
不过我不带着它也会记得你
But I don't need this to remember you by.
到了首府后会发生很多变化
Many things will change when we reach the capital, Ani...
但我对你的关心不会变
but my caring for you will remain.
我也会关心你的，只是我…
I care for you, too, only l...
你想你妈妈？
Miss your mother.
克罗肯特整个星球，就是一座大城市
Coruscant. The entire planet is one big city.
那是首相飞船
There's Chancellor Valorum's shuttle.
看那边，帕尔帕庭议员正等着我们
And look over there. Senator Palpatine is waiting for us.
看到你安然无恙我就放心了，女王陛下
It is a great gift to see you alive, Your Majesty.
通讯中断了，我们都很为你担心，
With the communications break down, we've been very concerned.
我很想听你带回的消息
I'm anxious to hear your report on the situation.
我来介绍：这位是首相维罗伦先生
May I present Supreme Chancellor Valorum.
欢迎你，女王陛下
Welcome, Your Highness.
很荣幸我终于见到你了
It's an honour to finally meet you in person.
谢谢你，首相
Thank you, Supreme Chancellor.
大家对目前的局势都感到忧心忡忡
I must relay to you how distressed everyone is over the current situation.
我召集了国会特别会议听取你的意见
I've called for a special session of the senate to hear your position.
让你多费心了，首相先生
I'm grateful for your concern, Chancellor.
议程中有个问题…
There is a question of procedure...
不过我还是相信能够解决的
but I'm confident we can overcome it.
我现在得马上去绝地长老院
I must speak with the Jedi Council immediately.
现在的情况变得越来越复杂了
The situation has become much more complicated.
安，走吧
Ani, come on.
女王心地不错，
Da queen's a bein grossly nice, mesa tinks.
真热闹
Pitty hot.
根本没有正义可言，只有政治
There is no civility, only politics.
共和国已经不是从前的共和国了
The Republic is not what it once was.
国会中尽是那些贪得无厌的议员
The senate is full of greedy, squabbling delegates.
他们根本不关心人民的利益
There is no interest in the common good.
老实说女王陛下
I must be frank, Your Majesty.
国会很难阻止贸易联盟的入侵行动
There is little chance the senate will act on the invasion.
维罗伦首相认为还有希望
Chancellor Valorum seems to think there is hope.
我就明说了吧，女王陛下…
If I may say so, Your Majesty...
首相其实并没有什么实权
the chancellor has little real power.
他被毫无根据的贪污控告所困住
He is mired by baseless accusations of corruption.
- 官僚现在掌握大权  - 我们有什么办法吗？
- The bureaucrats are in charge now. - What options have we?
首先我们应该马上重新选举出…
Our best choice would be to push for the election...
一位强干的共和国首相…
of a stronger supreme chancellor...
能约束那些贪官污吏…
one who could control the bureaucrats...
主持公道
and give us justice.
你可对维罗伦首相任职期间的工作投不信任票
You could call for a vote of no confidence in Chancellor Valorum.
他一直是我们强有力的支持者
He has been our strongest supporter.
那另外一个办法就是只有向法院起诉了
Our only other choice would be to submit a plea to the courts.
上法院比国会争论更花时间
The courts take even longer to decide things than the senate.
我们的人民面临死亡，议员先生
Our people are dying, Senator.
我们必须想办法马上阻止联盟的入侵
We must do something quickly to stop the Federation.
看现在这局去势，女王陛下
To be realistic, Your Majesty...
可我觉得还是接受联盟的控制…
I think we're going to have to accept Federation control...
就目前来说
for the time being.
这个我决不能接受
That is something I cannot do.
他的绝地技艺很好
He was trained in the Jedi arts.
他是个西斯人
My only conclusion can be that it was a Sith lord .
不可能
Impossible.
西斯人一千年前就灭绝了
The Sith have been extinct for a millennium.
我不相信，西斯人回来了我们会不知道？
I do not believe the Sith could have returned without us knowing.
那其中的阴暗面很难看到
Hard to see, the dark side is.
我们要尽全力解开这个谜
We will use all our resources to unravel this mystery.
我们要弄清那个武士的身份
We will discover the identity of your attacker.
愿力与你同在
May the Force be with you.
等一等，奎刚
Master Qui-Gon.
你还有什么要说的？
More to say have you?
请允许我说实话
With your permission, my master...
我发现原力在集结
I have encountered a vergence in the Force.
原力在集结？
A vergence, you say.
你是指在一个人的身上？
Located around a person?
是个孩子
A boy.
他的细胞中含有很高的超能素…
His cells have the highest concentration of midi-chlorians...
我以前从未见到过
I have seen in a life-form.
他也许就是由超能素孕育而生的
It is possible he was conceived by the midi-chlorians.
你提到那个大预言中说的那个给原力带来平衡的人
You refer to the prophecy of the one who will bring balance to the Force.
你相信就是这个孩子？
You believe it's this boy?
- 我并没有说… - 可你相信
- I don't presume to... - But you do.
你已经说得很明白
Revealed your opinion is.
请让他接受测试吧，师父
I request the boy be tested, Master.
你想把他训练成一个绝地武士吗？
Trained as a Jedi you request for him, hmm?
是原力让我找到他的
Finding him was the will of the Force.
我绝不怀疑的
I have no doubt of that.
那就把他带来吧
Bring him before us, then.
这个孩子要见帕德梅
The boy's here to see Padme
让他进来
Let him in.
对不起，安，但帕德梅现在不在
I'm sorry, Ani, but Padmes not here right now.
是谁？
Who is it?
安纳金・天行者来见帕德梅，女王陛下
Anakin Skywalker to see Padme Your Highness.
帕德梅为我办事去
I've sent Padme on an errand.
我现在要去绝地圣堂…
I'm on my way to the Jedi temple...
开始我的训练，但愿是吧
to start my training, I hope.
也许我再也见不到她了，所以来向她告别
I may never see her again, so I came to say goodbye.
我们会转达的 她一定会为你祝福
We will tell her for you. We are sure her heart goes with you.
谢谢您，女王陛下
Thank you, Your Highness.
主席认可这位来自纳布星球的议员
The chair recognizes the senator from the sovereign system of Naboo.
共和国首相，国会议员们…
Supreme Chancellor, delegates of the senate...
一场悲剧发生了…
a tragedy has occurred...
起因就是国会在贸易通道上征税…
which started right here with the taxation of trade routes...
并且现在吞并了我们整个星球…
and has now engulfed our entire planet...
在贸易联盟的巨大压力之下
in the oppression of the Trade Federation.
这么说太过分了！
This is outrageous!
我们反对这位议员的说法
I object to the senator's statements.
本主席现在还没允许贸易联盟的议员发言
The chair does not recognize the senator from the Trade Federation at this time.
为了表明我们的主张，我提出由阿米达拉女王…
To state our allegations, I present Queen Amidala...
她最近当选为纳布星的最高统治者…
recently elected ruler of the Naboo...
她的讲话代表了我方
who speaks on our behalf.
各位尊敬的共和国议员…
Honourable representatives of the Republic...
我是冒着生命危险来见各位的
I come to you under the gravest of circumstances.
纳布星球遭到了贸易联盟的入侵…
The Naboo system has been invaded by the droid armies of the Trade...
我反对！这话没有依据！
I object! There is no proof!
这是不可能的
This is incredible.
我们建议派代表团到纳布星去查明真相
We recommend a commission be sent to Naboo to ascertain the truth.
马拉斯代尔星球国会…
The Congress of Malastare...
同意尊敬的贸易联盟代表的意见
concurs with the honourable delegate from the Trade Federation.
应该派代表团去
A commission must be appointed.
- 问题是…  - 对不起，首相
- The point... - Excuse me, Chancellor.
就是这些官僚
Enter the bureaucrat.
他们在幕后操纵着国会
The true rulers of the Republic.
贸易联盟已经把他们都收买了
And on the payroll of the Trade Federation, I might add.
维罗伦首相拿这帮家伙一点办法也没有
This is where Chancellor Valorum's strength will disappear.
提议被采纳
The point is conceded.
等代表团查明真相以后
Will you defer your motion to allow a commission...
你也许会改变你的陈述
to explore the validity of your accusations?
我是不会改变的
I will not defer.
我是来请你们阻止他们的入侵行动的
I've come before you to resolve this attack on our sovereignty now.
我眼看着我的人民在受苦
I was not elected to watch my people suffer and die...
而你却在谈论什么代表团
while you discuss this invasion in a committee.
如果国会无力处理此事…
If this body is not capable of action...
我建议重选一位共和国首相
I suggest new leadership is needed.
我把完全不信任票投给…
I move for a vote of no confidence...
维罗伦首相的领导能力
in Chancellor Valorum's leadership.
立即投票！立即投票！
Vote now! Vote now!
秩序！
Order!
现在他们要选出一位新首相
Now they will elect a new chancellor...
一位能干的首相
a strong chancellor...
他应该能结束我们的悲剧
one who will not let our tragedy continue.
安纳金没能通过长老院的测试，他年龄太大了
The boy will not pass the council's test, Master. He's too old.
他会成为绝地武士的，我敢肯定
Anakin will become a Jedi, I promise you.
别再违背长老们的意愿了，
Do not defy the council, Master, not again.
有些事我必须做，欧比旺
I shall do what I must, Obi-Wan.
要是你守规矩，你早就已经当长老了
If you would just follow the code, you would be on the council.
他们这次是不会答应的
They will not go along with you this time.
你要学的东西还多着呐，你太年轻了
You still have much to learn, my young apprentice.
一艘船
A ship.
杯子
A cup.
是船
A ship.
摩托艇
A speeder.
有什么感觉？
How feel you?
感到冷
Cold, sir.
- 你害怕吗？ - 不害怕
- Afraid are you? - No, sir.
我们能看透你
See through you we can.
注意你自己的感觉
Be mindful of your feelings.
你的思想集中在你妈妈身上
Your thoughts dwell on your mother.
我很想她
I miss her.
害怕失去她，对吧？
Afraid to lose her, I think, mmm?
这和你们的测试有什么关系？
What has that got to do with anything?
当然有
Everything.
恐惧是原力的阴暗面
Fear is the path to the dark side.
恐惧导致愤怒，愤怒导致仇恨
Fear leads to anger. Anger leads to hate.
仇恨带来痛苦
Hate leads to suffering.
我感觉到你很恐惧
I sense much fear in you.
你觉得你的人民会面临死亡吗？
Yousa tinking yousa people ganna die?
不知道
I don't know.
冈根人也会被杀死吗？
Gungans get pasted too, eh?
但愿不会
I hope not.
冈根人是绝不会坐以待毙的
Gungans no die'n without a fight.
我们都是战土
Wesa warriors.
我们有庞大的军队
Wesa got a grand army.
所以他们都喜欢我们，陛下
Dat's why you no liken us, mesa tinks.
女王陛下？
Your Highness?
女王陛下…
Your Highness...
帕尔帕庭议员被提名参加…
Senator Palpatine has been nominated to succeed Valorum...
下一任首相的选举
as supreme chancellor.
真没想到，不过的确是个好消息
A surprise, to be sure, but a welcome one.
女王陛下，如果我当选
Your Majesty, if I am elected,
我保证一定要惩治腐败
I promise to put an end to corruption.
被提名的还有谁？
Who else has been nominated?
奥德兰星的贝尔・安德烈斯
Bail Antilles of Alderaan
和马拉斯代尔星的安利・蒂姆
and Ainlee Teem of Malastare.
我确信我们的处境将会得到大量的同情票
I feel confident our situation will create a strong sympathy vote for us.
我会成为首相的
I will be chancellor.
我担心等到你掌握国会大权的时候
I fear by the time you have control of the bureaucrats, Senator...
我们纳布星的人民已经惨遭灭绝了
there'll be nothing left of our people, our way of life.
你的担心我很理解
I understand your concern, Your Majesty.
不幸的是联盟已经控制了纳布星
Unfortunately, the Federation has possession of our planet.
这里是你的战场
Senator, this is your arena.
我觉得我还是回去我的
I feel I must return to mine.
我决定回纳布星去
I've decided to go back to Naboo.
回去？
Go back?
陛下，现实一点，贸易联盟的人会强迫你签协议的
But, Your Majesty, be realistic. They'll force you to sign the treaty.
我什么协议也不会签
I will sign no treaty, Senator.
我要和我的人民生死与共
My fate will be no different than that of our people.
- 船长 - 女王陛下
- Captain. - Your Highness.
- 备好我的飞船 - 求你了，陛下
- Ready my ship. - Please, Your Majesty.
请你留下来，这里才安全
Stay here where it's safe.
很明显，国会已经失去它的作用了
It is clear to me now that the Republic no longer functions.
希望你能重新唤起国会的理智和同情心
I pray you will bring sanity and compassion back to the senate.
他体内的原力很强
The Force is strong with him.
那他可以受训了，是吗？
He is to be trained, then?
不，他不能接受训练
No, he will not be trained.
为什么？
No?
他年龄太大
He is too old.
他是命中注定的，这你应该知道
He is the chosen one. You must see it.
这孩子的未来乌云密布
Clouded this boy's future is.
我要训练他
I will train him, then.
我要收安纳金肯做我的徒弟
I take Anakin as my Padawan learner.
你已经有一个徒弟了，奎刚
An apprentice you have, Qui-Gon.
不能再收第二个了
Impossible to take on a second.
这不合规矩
The code forbids it.
- 欧比旺已经准备好了 - 我己准备好接受考验了
- Obi-Wan is ready. - I am ready to face the trials.
我们长老院将自己安排谁该接受考验
Our own counsel we will keep on who is ready.
他虽然脾气倔，关于原力还有很多要学的…
He is headstrong and he has much to learn of the living Force...
但他很有能力
but he is capable.
我已经没有什么可教他的了
There is little more he can learn from me.
小天行者的命运以后再做决定吧
Young Skywalker's fate will be decided later.
现在不是时候
Now is not the time for this.
国会正在选举新的首相
The senate is voting for a new supreme chancellor...
阿米达拉女王准备返回纳布星…
and Queen Amidala is returning home...
这会对联盟产生压力，冲突可能会扩大
which puts pressure on the Federation and could widen the confrontation.
并且可能把那个武士引出来
And draw out the queen's attacker.
和女王一起去纳布星，查明那位神秘武士的身份
Go with the queen to Naboo and discover the identity of this dark warrior.
这是我们揭开西斯人
This is the clue we need...
神秘面纱的重要线索
to unravel the mystery of the Sith.
原动力与你同在
May the Force be with you.
这不是不尊重你，师父，这是事实
It's not disrespect, Master. It's the truth.
你是你的看法
From your point of view.
那孩子很危险，他们都感觉到了，你怎么就不能？
The boy is dangerous. They all sense it. Why can't you?
他的命运还没有决定，他并不危险
His fate is uncertain. He's not dangerous.
长老院要决定那孩子的命运
The council will decide Anakin's future.
这你满意了吧，好了，上船吧
That should be enough for you. Now get on board .
奎刚先生，我真的不想给你添麻烦
Qui-Gon, sir, I don't want to be a problem.
你没有，安
You won't be, Ani.
他们不想让我训练你…
I'm not allowed to train you...
你可以看我怎么做
so I want you to watch me and be mindful.
永远记住:
Always remember:
专注程度决定了一切
Your focus determines your reality.
紧跟着我，你不会有危险的
Stay close to me and you'll be safe.
奎刚师父
Master, sir...
我听见尤达师父在说什么超能素
I heard Yoda talking about midi-chlorians.
我一直想知道… 什么是超能素？
I've been wondering... What are midi-chlorians?
所谓超能素是指生活在…
Midi-chlorians are a microscopic life-form...
生命细胞中的一种微生物体
that resides within all living cells.
- 它们在我身体里吗？ - 对，在你的细胞里
- They live inside me? - Inside your cells, yes.
- 我们和它是共生关系 - 共生关系？
- And we are symbionts with them. - Symbionts?
也就是共同生存互相利用的生命体
Life-forms living together for mutual advantage.
没有超能素，生命就不存在了…
Without the midi-chlorians, life could not exist...
我们也就就失去了原力
and we would have no knowledge of the Force.
是超能素源源不断的
They continually speak to us...
给我们提供的原力
telling us the will of the Force.
只要你静下心来
When you learn to quiet your mind...
你就能感觉到它们
you'll hear them speaking to you.
我还是不明白
I don't understand.
训练一段时间后，你就明白了
With time and training, Ani, you will. You will.
女王陛下，我们很荣幸能为你继续保驾护航
Your Majesty, it is our pleasure to continue to serve and protect you.
谢谢你的帮助
I welcome your help.
帕尔帕庭议员担心贸易联盟企图杀死我
Senator Palpatine fears that the Federation means to destroy me.
我不会让他们得逞的
I assure you I will not allow that to happen.
要回家了！
Wesa goin' home!
走吧，R2
Come on, R2.
占领纳布星了吗？
Is the planet secure?
我们刚刚占领了最后几个土着人的聚居点
We have taken over the last pockets of primitive life-forms.
我们已经完全控制了纳布星
We are in complete control of the planet now.
很好 还要保证继续让国会…
Good. I will see to it that in the senate...
受我们的操纵…
things stay as they are.
我会派我的徒弟，达斯・摩尔，跟你们一起去
I am sending my apprentice, Darth Maul, to join you.
是，大人
Yes, my lord .
西斯人要来？
A Sith here?
那些是前进稳定器
Those are the forward stabilizers.
那两个是控制高度的？
And those two control the pitch?
你学得可真快
You catch on pretty quick.
我们一着陆…
As soon as we land...
贸易联盟的人就会强迫你在他们的协议上签字的
the Federation will arrest you and force you to sign the treaty.
是的
I agree.
我不知道你这样做有什么意义
I'm not sure what you wish to accomplish by this.
我要回去收复失地
I will take back what's ours.
我们的人太少，女王陛下
There are too few of us, Your Highness.
而且我们又没有军队
We have no army.
我仅能保护你的人生安全
And I can only protect you.
但我不能为你去打仗
I can't fight a war for you.
加加・宾克斯
Jar Jar Binks.
叫我吗，女王陛下？
Mesa, Your Highness?
是的，我需要你的帮助
Yes. I need your help.
发现了一艘战舰
I have one battleship on my scope.
是由机器人驾驶的
It's a droid control ship.
他们可能已经发现我们了
They've probably spotted us.
我们的时间不多了
We haven't much time.
加加正在赶往冈根城，师父
Jar Jar is on his way to the Gungan city, Master.
很好
Good.
你觉得女王的计划能行吗？
Do you think the queen's idea will work?
冈根人不是那么好动摇的
The Gungans will not be easily swayed.
我们也不能用我们的力量帮助她
And we cannot use our power to help her.
我… 我向你道歉，师父
I'm sorry for my behaviour, Master.
关于那孩子我不该对你的意见表示异议
It's not my place to disagree with you about the boy.
你觉我可以接受考验了，我很感激
And I am grateful you think I'm ready to take the trials.
你是个好徒弟，欧比旺
You've been a good apprentice, Obi-Wan.
你的智慧已经超过我了
And you're a much wiser man than I am.
你会成会一个伟大的绝地武士
I foresee you will become a great Jedi knight.
那儿一个人也没有
Desa nobody dare!
冈根城是空的
The Gungan city is deserted!
我看是打过仗了
Some kinda fight, mesa tinks.
他们是被送到集中营去了吧？
Do you think they have been taken to the camps?
也可能是被消灭了
More likely they were wiped out.
- 我可不这么看 - 知道他们在哪儿，扎扎？
- Mesa no tink so. - Do you know where they are, Jar Jar?
有危险的时候冈根人就会去圣地
When in trouble, Gungans go to sacred place.
我带你们去，走啊，跟我来
Mesa show you. Come on. Mesa show you!
首领大人，纳布星的阿米达拉女王到
Your Honour, Queen Amidala of the Naboo.
你好啊，纳斯大首领，我的大人
Heyo dadee Big Boss Nass, Your Honour.
加加宾克斯
Jar Jar Binks.
这些都是些什么人啦？
Who's da uss-en uthers?
我是纳布星的阿米达拉女王
I am Queen Amidala of the Naboo.
我们到这儿来没有敌意
I come before you in peace.
纳布大人物
Ah, Naboo biggen.
是你们把机器人部队带来的
Yousa bringen da Mackineeks.
自以为了不起吗？
Yousa all bombad.
我们找到这儿来是想和你结盟的
We have searched you out because we wish to form an alliance.
首领大人
Your Honour.
你是谁？
Whosa dis?
我是阿米达拉女王
I am Queen Amidala.
她是我的替身…
This is my decoy...
是保护我的，她是我忠诚的保镖
my protection, my loyal bodyguard.
很抱歉欺骗你，但这是保护我自己的必要手段
I'm sorry for my deception, but it was necessary to protect myself.
虽然我们之间也有分歧，首领大人…
Although we do not always agree, Your Honour...
但我们之间一直是相安无事的
our two great societies have always lived in peace.
贸易联盟毁灭了我们所有辛苦工作的成果
The Trade Federation has destroyed all that we have worked so hard to build.
如果不马上采取行动，后果将不堪设想
If we do not act quickly, all will be lost forever.
我请你帮助我们
I ask you to help us.
不，我求你帮助我们
No, I beg you to help us.
我们是你卑下的奴仆
We are your humble servants.
我们的命运掌握在你手里
Our fate is in your hands.
你们不觉得你们自己比我们冈根人优越了？
Yousa no tinken yousa greater den da Gungans?
这我很高兴！
Mesa lika dis!
也许…
Maybe...
我们…
wesa...
能成为朋友
being friends.
我们派出了巡逻艇
We've sent our patrols.
在沼泽地发现了他们的飞船
We already located their starship in the swamp.
就要找到他们了，大人
It won't be long, my lord .
没想到她会回纳布星
This is an unexpected move for her.
这也太冒险了
It 's too aggressive.
达斯摩罗，你要当心
Lord Maul, be mindful.
让他们先动手
Let them make the first move.
是的，大人
Yes, my master.
他们来了！
Deysa comin!
知道了！
All right!
他们来了！
They're here!
很好，他们到了
Good. They made it.
你干得真不错
Yousa doen grand.
加加让我们和纳布人结成同盟
Jar Jar bring uss-en and da Naboo together.
不，不，不，不
Oh, no, no, no.
所以，现在我任命你为…
So, wesa make you...
冈根的大将军
bombad general.
将军？
General?
船长
Captain.
- 女王陛下 - 情况怎么样？
- Your Highness. - What is the situation?
人们都被关在集中营里
Almost everyone's in camps.
一些警察和卫兵秘密组成了地下抵抗抵抗组织
A few hundred police and guards formed an underground resistance movement.
我尽量把抵抗组职的头领带来了
I brought back as many of the leaders as I could.
贸易联盟的军队比我想像的…
The Federation army's also much larger than we thought...
强大得多
and much stronger.
女王陛下，这场战斗我们很难取胜
Your Highness, this is a battle I do not think that we can win.
战斗只是个幌子
The battle is a diversion.
冈根人会把机器人部队引到城外
The Gungans must draw the droid army away from the cities.
Ｒ２
R2.
我们可以通过瀑布下面的秘密通道进到城里
We can enter the city using the secret passages on the waterfall side.
我们一到主要入口…
Once we get to the main entrance...
船长就开始进行佯政
Captain Panaka will create a diversion.
之后我们就进入宫殿抓住总督
Then we can enter the palace and capture the viceroy.
没有了总督，他们就会乱作一团
Without the viceroy, they will be lost and confused.
你怎么看的，绝地大师？
What do you think, Master Jedi?
宫殿一定会戒备森严的
The viceroy will be well-guarded.
我们得想办法进入正殿
The difficulty is getting into the throne room.
只要一进去，就不会有什么问题了
Once we're inside, we shouldn't have a problem.
进行佯攻损失会很大，很多冈根人可能会战死
There is a possibility, with this diversion, many Gungans will be killed.
我们冈根人是不怕牺牲的
Wesa ready to do our-san part.
我们有一个计划，可以瓦解机器人部队
We have a plan which should immobilize the droid army.
我们要派战斗机
We will send what pilots we have...
去摧毁控制机器人部队的指挥舰
to knock out the droid control ship orbiting the planet.
计划倒是不错，可那太冒险了
A well-conceived plan. However, there's great risk.
你们的武器很难穿透他们的防护罩
The weapons on your fighters may not penetrate the shields.
还有一个更大的危险
There's an even bigger danger.
如果总督逃脱了，女王陛下…
If the viceroy escapes, Your Highness...
他会带更多的机器人部队来这里的
he will return with another droid army.
所以我们抓捕总督的行动，一定要成功
Well, that is why we must not fail to get the viceroy.
这是我们成败的关键
Everything depends on it.
女王比我想像的还要傻
She is more foolish than I thought.
我们派出了所有部队…
We are sending all troops...
到沼泽地集结，准备迎敌
to meet this army assembling near the swamp.
他们的军队似乎都是土着人
It appears to be made up of primitives.
这对我们十分有利
This will work to our advantage.
同意我对他们发起进攻吗？
I have your approval to proceed, then, my lord ?
消灭他们
Wipe them out.
一个不留
All of them.
听着
Halt!
启动防护罩
Starting up the shield.
开火
Open fire.
等我们一进去，你就找个安全的地方躲起来
Once we get inside, you find a safe place to hide and stay there.
- 好的 - 别乱跑
- Sure. - Stay there.
开火，开火
Roger, roger.
我以为战场会离这儿很远呐
I thought the battle was going to take place far from here.
这也太近了
This is too close.
安，快躲起来
Ani, find cover.
- 快！ - 快上飞艇！
- Quick! - Get to your ships!
注意前方敌机
Fighters straight ahead.
收到，2号明白
Roger, Bravo Leader.
停火
Cease fire.
稳住，稳住
Steady. Steady.
- 启动机器人 - 是，长官
- Activate the droids. - Yes, sir.
噢，天哪
Ouch time.
开火
Fire!
我猜总督就在正殿里
My guess is the viceroy's in the throne room.
红队！蓝队！
Red group! Blue group!
大家都到这边来！
Everybody, this way!
喂，等等我
Hey, wait for me!
安，别出来，呆在座舱里
Anakin, stay where you are. You'll be safe there.
- 可是我…  - 那儿很安全
- But I... - Stay in that cockpit.
- 我们来对付他 - 我们绕道过去
- We'll handle this. - We'll take the long way.
我也可以干点什么，对吧，R2
We gotta do something, R2.
我找了，可我找不到开关
I'm trying to! I don't know where the trigger is!
噢，不是那个，也许是这个
Oops, wrong one. Maybe it's this one.
不，等等，是这个
Nope. Wait. Here it is.
快走
Let's go!
噢，是自动驾驶的
It's on automatic pilot.
我想自己驾驶
Try to override it.
不能在这耽搁太久，船长
We don't have time for this, Captain.
看，他们在那儿
Look, there they are.
所以他就自动飞到这儿来了
That's where the autopilot's taking us.
蠢机器人，我踢死你！
Dumb droid. Take that!
走开！走开！走开！
Get off! Get off! Get off!
走开！
Get off!
他们的导向防护罩很坚固
The deflector shield is too strong.
真够紧张的啊！
This is tense!
R2，别让他自动驾驶了
R2, get us off this autopilot.
那样我门都会把命送掉的
It's gonna get us both killed.
你做到了，R2！
You did it, R2!
好，咱们往左飞
Let's go left.
回去？
Go back?
奎刚让我呆在座舱里，我也没出去呀
Qui-Gon told me to stay in this cockpit, so that's what I'm gonna do.
我转一圈 晃他们一下
I'll try spinning. That's a good trick.
我知道很危险，坐稳了
I know we're in trouble. Just hang on.
走！
Go!
换钩枪！
Ascension guns!
撤退！快跑！
Retreat! Retreat!
这下糟了
Dis is nutsen.
超大的能源球
Uh-oh. Big boomers.
拉兄弟一把！
Give me a lift!
加加，用能源球！
Jar Jar, usen da booma!
什么？没有能源球！
What? Mesa no have a booma!
给你，用这个
Here. Taken dis one.
加加！
Jar Jar!
快跳，加加，快跳！
Jump, Jar Jar, jump!
放下武器吧 这一仗他们赢了
Put down your weapons. They win this round.
我们被打中了
We're hit, R2!
快停下来，快停下来
I'm trying to stop! I'm trying to stop!
发动机过热了
Everything's overheated.
不 这可不太妙
Oops. This is not good.
别投降，大将军
No giben up, General Jar Jar.
我正在想办法
Mesa think of something.
举起手来，我投降了
Hands up.
我投降了 我投降了
My give up. My give up.
你的小暴动该结束了，女王陛下
Your little insurrection is at an end, Your Highness.
是该你签署协议的时候了
Time for you to sign the treaty
并结束国会里那些毫无意义的争论
and end this pointless debate in the senate.
总督！
Viceroy!
你的任职到期了
Your occupation here has ended.
抓住她，这个女王是假的
After her. This one's a decoy.
船长
Captain!
关上大门
Jam the doors.
总督，我们现在该签署一个新协议了
Now, Viceroy, we will discuss a new treaty.
好了！有能源了，启动防护罩
Yes! We have power. Shields up.
尝尝这个！
Take this!
还有这个！
And this!
- 不 - 我们正在失去能源
- Oops. - We're losing power.
主反应堆好像有问题
There seems to be a problem with the main reactor.
不可能！
Impossible!
我们的防护罩是坚不可摧的
Nothing can get through our shield.
咱们赶快离开这儿
Let's get outta here.
怎么回事？ 好像是里边爆炸了！
What's that? It's blowing up from the inside!
不是我们打中的
We didn't hit it.
这比赛艇还要过瘾
Now, this is Podracing.
看，一艘我们的飞艇，在主货舱外面！
Look, one of ours, out of the main hold!
怎么回事？
What the...
他们怎么啦？
Was'n they doing?
他们的指挥舰被炸毁了 看！
The control ship has been destroyed. Look!
他们都死了
They all broke-ed.
不，已经太晚了
No, it's too late.
- 不 - 欧比旺
- No. - Obi-Wan.
答应我…
Promise...
答应我训练这个孩子
Promise me you will train the boy.
是的，师父
Yes, Master.
他是被选中的
He is the chosen one.
他会带来平衡
He will bring balance.
训练他
Train him.
总督先生…
Now, Viceroy...
现在你该回去向国会去解释这一切了
you're going to have to go back to the senate and explain all this.
我想你也该和你的贸易特权说再见了
I think you can kiss your trade franchise goodbye.
你是个好徒弟，欧比旺
You've been a good apprentice, Obi-Wan.
还有你，小天行者
And you, young Skywalker.
你们的技艺和勇气令人折服
We will watch your career with great interest.
祝贺你当选为共和国首相
Congratulations on your election, Chancellor.
是你救了我们的人民，女王陛下
Your boldness has saved our people, Your Majesty.
我应该向你表示祝贺
It's you who should be congratulated.
让我们携手为共和国带来和平与繁荣
Together we shall bring peace and prosperity to the Republic.
要长老院授予你绝地武士称号这不成问题
Confer on you the level of Jedi knight the council does.
可是你要我同意你收那个孩子做徒弟…
But agree with your taking this boy as your Padawan learner...
这个绝对不成
I do not.
他是奎刚看中的
Qui-Gon believed in him.
他也许是大预言中所说的人
The chosen one the boy may be.
不管怎样
Nevertheless...
可是训练他我认为是很危险的
grave danger I fear in his training.
尤达大师，我向奎刚保证过
Master Yoda, I gave Qui-Gon my word .
我要训练安纳金
I will train Anakin.
不管长老院同意还是不同意
Without the approval of the council, if I must.
你跟你师父奎刚一样固执
Qui-Gon's defiance I sense in you.
你没必要这样做
Need that you do not.
长老院同意你的请求
Agree with you the council does.
天行者是你的徒弟了
Your apprentice Skywalker will be.
现在这是要干什么？
What will happen to me now?
长老院已经同意我训练你
The council have granted me permission to train you.
你会成为一名绝地武士
You will be a Jedi, I promise.
毫无疑问，神秘武士是个西斯人
There's no doubt the mysterious warrior was a Sith.
他们总是有两个人
Always two there are.
不多，也不少
No more, no less.
一个师父和一个徒弟
A master and an apprentice.
可是被毁掉的是谁呢？
But which was destroyed?
师父还是徒弟？
The master or the apprentice?
你们好，各位！
Hello, everybody!
和平！
Peace!
我靠！
Ya-hoo!